- 让我们谈谈变压器的碳足迹。
- So let's talk about the carbon footprint of transformers.
也许你看过这样的头条新闻
Maybe you've seen headlines such as this one
训练单个 AI 模型可以排放尽可能多的碳
that training a single AI model can emit as much carbon
作为他们一生中的五辆汽车。
as five cars in their lifetimes.
那么什么时候是真的，而且总是真的吗？
So when is this true and is it always true?
好吧，这实际上取决于几件事。
Well, it actually depends on several things.
最重要的是，这取决于
Most importantly, it depends
关于你使用的能源类型。
on the type of energy you're using.
如果你使用的是可再生能源，例如
If you're using renewable energy such as
太阳能、风能、水力发电，你真的
solar, wind, hydroelectricity, you're really
根本不排放任何碳，非常非常少。
not emitting any carbon at all, very, very little.
如果你使用的是煤炭等不可再生能源
If you're using non-renewable energy sources such as coal
那么他们的碳足迹要高得多
then their carbon footprint is a lot higher
因为本质上你正在排放大量的温室气体。
'cuz essentially you are emitting a lot of greenhouse gases.
另一个方面是训练时间。
Another aspect is training time.
所以你训练的时间越长，消耗的能量就越多
So the longer you train, the more energy you use
你使用的能源越多，你排放的碳就越多，对吗？
the more energy you use, the more carbon you emit, right?
所以这真的加起来
So this really adds up
特别是如果你正在训练大型模型
especially if you're training large models for
数小时、数天和数周。
for hours and days and weeks.
你使用的硬件也很重要
The hardware you use also matters
因为例如某些 GPU 效率更高
because some GPUs, for example, are more efficient
比其他人和利用效率使用得当。
than others and utilizing efficiency use properly.
所以一直百分百地使用它们
So using them a hundred percent all the time
可以真正减少你的能源消耗。
can really reduce the energy consumption that you have.
然后再次减少你的碳足迹。
And then once again, reduce your carbon footprint.
还有其他方面比如 IO
There's also other aspects such as IO
比如数据，等等，等等。
such as data, et cetera, et cetera.
但这些是你应该关注的主要三个。
But these are the main three that you should focus on.
所以当我谈论能源和碳强度时
So when I talk about energy sources and carbon intensity
那个的真实意义是什么？
what does that really mean?
所以如果你看屏幕顶部
So if you look at the top of the screen
你有碳足迹
you have a carbon footprint
印度孟买的云计算实例
of a cloud computing instance in Mumbai, India
每千瓦时排放 920 克二氧化碳。
which emits 920 grams of CO2 per kilowatt hour.
这差不多一公斤
This is almost one kilogram
每千瓦时电力使用的二氧化碳排放量。
of CO2 per kilowatt hour of electricity used.
如果你把它与加拿大相比，蒙特利尔
If you compare that with Canada, Montreal
我现在所在的位置，每千克小时排放 20 克二氧化碳。
where I am right now, 20 grams of CO2 per kilo hour.
所以这是一个非常非常大的区别。
So that's a really, really big difference.
碳排放量几乎增加了 40 倍
Almost more than 40 times more carbon emitted
在孟买对蒙特利尔。
in Mumbai versus Montreal.
所以这真的可以加起来。
And so this can really, really add up.
例如，如果你要训练一个模型数周
If you're training a model for weeks, for example
你乘以 40
you're multiplying times 40
你排放的碳。
the carbon that you're emitting.
所以选择合适的实例
So choosing the right instance
选择低碳计算实例
choosing a low carbon compute instance
这真的是你能做的最有影响力的事情。
is really the most impactful thing that you can do.
这就是它真正可以加起来的地方
And this is where it can really add up
如果你正在接受非常密集的训练
if you're training in a very intensive
在一个非常碳密集的地区
in a very carbon intensive region
其他要考虑的因素，例如
other elements to consider, for example
使用预训练模型
using pre-trained models
这就是回收的机器学习等价物。
that's the machine learning equivalent of recycling.
当你有可用的预训练模型时
When you have pre-trained models available using them
你根本没有排放任何碳，对吧？
you're not emitting any carbon at all, right?
你没有再训练任何东西。
You're not retraining anything.
所以这也在做你的功课
So that's also doing your homework
并环顾四周已经存在的东西。
and kind of looking around what already exists.
微调而不是从头开始训练。
Fine tuning instead of training from scratch.
所以再一次
So once again
如果你找到几乎是你需要的模型
if you find a model that is almost what you need
但对最后几层的调整不是很精细
but not quite fine tuning the last couple of layers
让它真正适合你的目的
making it really fit your purpose instead
培训大型变压器
of training a large transformer
从头开始真的很有帮助，
from scratch can really help,
从较小的实验开始
starting with smaller experiments
并边调试边调试。
and debugging as you go.
这意味着，例如，培训
So that means, for example, training
弄清楚数据编码，弄清楚，你知道
figuring out data encoding, figuring out, you know
确保没有小错误，你会
making sure that there's no small bugs, that you'll
你会意识到，你知道，经过 16 个小时的训练
you'll realize, you know, 16 hours into training
从小事做起，真正确保
starting small and really making sure
你在做什么，你的代码是什么，是稳定的。
that what you're doing, what your code is, is stable.
然后最后做一个文献综述
And then finally doing a literature review to
选择超参数范围，然后跟随
choose hyper parameter ranges and then following
使用随机搜索而不是网格搜索。
up with a random search instead of a grid search.
所以随机搜索超参数
So random searches for hyper parameters
组合实际上被证明是有效的
combinations have actually shown to be as efficient
在寻找最佳配置作为网格搜索时。
in finding the optimal configuration as grid search.
但显然你并没有尝试所有可能的组合
But obviously you're not trying all possible combinations
你只是在尝试其中的一部分。
you're only trying a subset of them.
所以这也很有帮助。
So this can really help as well.
所以现在如果我们回去
So now if we go back
2019 年 Strubell 等人的原始论文
to the original paper by Strubell et all in 2019
臭名昭著的五辆车在他们一生的论文中。
the infamous five cars in their lifetimes paper.
如果你只是看
If you just look
在一个 2 亿周边变压器的变压器处
at a transformer of 200 million perimeter transformer
它的碳足迹约为 200 磅二氧化碳
it is carbon footprint is around 200 pounds of CO2
这很重要
which is significant
但它离五辆汽车还差得很远，对吧？
but it's nowhere near five cars, right?
这甚至不是跨大西洋航班。
It's not even a transatlantic flight.
它真正加起来的方式是当你在做的时候
How it really adds up is when you're doing
神经架构搜索
neural architecture search
当你进行超参数调整时，以及
when you're doing hyper parameter tuning, and
这是在尝试所有可能的组合
this is trying all possible combinations
等等，等等。
et cetera, et cetera.
这是哪里
And this is where
就像来自 600,000 磅的二氧化碳一样。
like the 600,000 pounds of CO2 came from.
所以这真的是事情加起来的地方。
So this is really where things add up.
所以，但如果你正念认真地做事
So, but if you're doing things mindfully and conscientiously
那么你的碳足迹就不会那么大，
then your carbon footprint wont be as big as,
正如本文所暗示的，一些工具可以用来计算
as the paper implied, some tools to figure
计算出你排放的 CO2 量。
out how much CO2 exactly you're emitting.
有一个基于网络的工具叫做 machine
There's a web-based tool called machine
学习提交计算器，它可以让你
learning submissions calculator, which allows you
手动输入，例如，你使用的硬件
to manually input, for example, which hardware you used
你用了多少小时
how many hours you used it for
它位于本地或云端。
where it was located locally or in the cloud.
然后它会给你一个估计
And then it's gonna give you an estimate
你排放了多少二氧化碳。
of how much CO2 you emitted.
另一个以编程方式执行此操作的工具，
Another tool that does this programmatically,
称为代号碳。
is called code carbon.
所以你可以 PIP 安装它，你可以，你可以去 GitHub
So you can PIP install it, you can, you can go to the GitHub
本质上它与你的代码并行运行。
and essentially it runs in parallel to your code.
所以基本上你称之为
So essentially you call it
然后你做所有的训练。
and then you do all your training.
然后最后它会给你一个估计
And then at the end it's gonna give you an estimate
包含排放量估算值的 CSV 文件。
a CSV file with an estimate of your emissions.
它会给你一些比较。
And it's gonna give you some comparisons.
它有一个可视化用户界面，你可以在其中真正看到
It's got a visual UI where you can really look
这与开车或看电视相比如何。
at how this compares to driving a car or watching TV.
所以它可以给你一个想法
So it can give you an idea
你的排放范围也是如此。
of the scope of your emissions as well.
实际上，code carbon 已经集成到汽车中
And actually, code carbon is already integrated into auto
和 LP，希望人们会使用它
and LP and hopefully people will be using it
开箱即用，轻松跟踪所有排放
out of the box and easily tracking their emissions all
通过培训和部署变压器。
through training and deploying transformers.